<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albena Azmanova</title>
    <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Albena Azmanova</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 21:54:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 20:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a writer, scholar and political commentator interested in social justice and political judgment, the rise of new ideologies, and democracy&amp;rsquo;s troubles with capitalism. I draw on history, philosophy and sociology as I seek to produce politically salient and critical analyses of modern societies. I am currently a Professor of Social and Political Science at the University of Kent’s Brussels School of International Studies, and honorary fellow at the Institute for Global Sustainable Development, University of Warwick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Articles &amp; Book Chapters</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/articles_and_book_chapters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 20:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/articles_and_book_chapters/</guid>
      <description>The ends of radical critique? Crisis, capitalism, emancipation: a conversation&#xA;Capitalism on Edge: How Fighting Precarity Can Achieve Radical Change Without Crisis or Utopia&#xA;Populism and the Recasting of the Ideological Landscape of Liberal Democracies&#xA;Postcapitalism: The Return of Radical Critique&#xA;Regaining Control Over Precarity&#xA;Battlegrounds of Justice: The Pandemic and What Really Grieves the 99%&#xA;Countering precarity: social resilience through a political economy of trust&#xA;Viral Insurgencies: Can Capitalism Survive Covid?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le social dans quel etat?</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/events/le_social_dans_quel_etat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 21:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/events/le_social_dans_quel_etat/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Speech vs Free Speech Higher Educations False Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/opeds/safe-speech-vs-free-speech-higher-educations-false-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/opeds/safe-speech-vs-free-speech-higher-educations-false-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>In the ‘cancel culture’ era, universities should remember that the original purpose of free speech was to empower the weak, not to shelter them</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitalism, democracy, socialism</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/books/capitalism_democracy_socialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/books/capitalism_democracy_socialism/</guid>
      <description>This book, collectively authored by members of the Research Committee on Socialism, Capitalism and Democracy (part of the International Political Science Association) critically analyzes the current historical conjuncture with an eye to its emergent alternatives.&#xA;Table of Contents:&#xA;Introduction: “Democracy, Capitalism, Socialism, or none of the above – deciphering history’s tremors.” Albena Azmanova and James Chamberlain&#xA;1/ “Capitalism and Democracy: Complementarity, Complicity, Conflict, Compatibility.” Brian Milstein&#xA;2/ “Privatization and the Governance of the Commons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Overview</title>
      <link>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://azmanov.github.io/albena_site_clone/research/</guid>
      <description>My intellectual objective has been to elaborate a formula of critique for politically valiant social analysis, suitable for the conceptualization of radical social change. The evolution of this project is articulated below, referenced to the relevant publications.&#xA;My efforts at politically engaged philosophical reflection began with my involvement with the dissident movements in my native Bulgaria in the late 1980s. I observed a continuity between the nascent post-communist democracy and the old regime, questioning prevalent at the time optimistic prognoses for the future of liberal democracy in Eastern Europe (Azmanova 1992).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
